Guide to the Fraternities and Sororities collection, 1931-2001 UA.01.11.0087
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Fraternities and Sororities collection
1931-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0087
5.5 Linear Feet
This artificial reference collection contains materials from student service and social fraternities and sororities of Trinity College and Duke University from about 1931 to 2001. Types of materials include profiles, handbooks, correspondence, clippings, flyers, newsletters, composite photographs, and miscellaneous writings relating to student life in Greek letter societies at Duke University. General topics include rush, alcohol policies, hazing, critiques of the Greek system, and chapter establishment and governance. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
No restrictions.
Provenance
Compiled files from University Archives collections; 1980 (accession number: 80-83).
Gift; 1980; 80-183.
Transfer; 1988; A88-0053.
Gift; 1989; A89-0047.
Gift; 1991; A91-11.
Gift; 1994; A94-9.
Historical Note
Fraternities and sororities have historically been a large part of campus life at Duke University by sponsoring inter-campus events, hosting parties, and performing community service. They are known for providing leadership opportunities and fostering a sense of belonging among a large student body. The first fraternities and sororities on campus were a part of Trinity College (1859-1924), the precursor to Duke University. The earliest fraternity chapter on campus was the Xi Chapter of Alpha Tau Omega, chartered in 1872 (at Trinity College, then located in Randolph County, N.C.). The earliest sorority chapter on campus (then Trinity College) was the Omicron Chapter of Alpha Delta Pi, chartered in 1911.
Fraternities and sororities at Duke are governed by the Interfraternity Council, the National Pan-Hellenic Council, and the Panhellenic Association. There also exist cultural Greek letter organizations which are not formally governed. The Interfraternity Council at Duke University is the local umbrella organization for national fraternities at Duke University. The National Pan-Hellenic Council serves as the governing body for historically African American fraternities and sororities at Duke University. The Duke Panhellenic Association is the organizing body of the National Panhellenic Council sororities on campus.
Collection Overview
This artificial reference collection contains profiles, handbooks, correspondence, clippings, flyers, newsletters, composite photographs, and miscellaneous writings pertaining to fraternities and sororities at Duke University. Materials range in date from 1931-2001.
Related Material
Interfraternity Council records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Panhellenic Council records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Hazing; Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham; Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.); Greek letter societies; College students -- Alcohol use -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.; Duke University -- Societies, etc.; Duke University. University Archives; Duke University
- Greek life at Duke University, general subject files, 1952-1989.
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes clippings, rush handbooks, general flyers, a history of fraternity housing locations, and student evaluations of sororities. Also contains correspondence between fraternities, sororities, and Duke University regarding campus policies.
  - Big Brother/Sister (IFC-Panhel) Program, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Chapter establishment, general (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1975-2001, undated (Box 1)
  - Evaluations of sororities (Box 1)
  - Flyers (Box 1)
  - Greek Week (Box 1)
  - Handbooks, 1952-1964 (Box 1)
  - Handbooks, 1966-1989 (Box 1)
  - Hazing (Box 1)
  - Housing (Box 1)
  - InterFraternity Council, 1968-1984 (Box 1)
  - Panhellenic Council, general (Box 1)
- Fraternities and Sororities, 1923-1998.
  Includes small collections of material from and about individual fraternities and sororities. Collections include clippings, flyers, membership lists, business meeting notes, newsletters, and pledge books. Also contains correspondence between sororities, fraternities, and their governing bodies.
  Arrangement note
  Ordered alphabetically by group name.
  - Alpha Epsilon Phi (Box 1)
  - Alpha Chi Omega (Box 1)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi Omega (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha (Box 1)
  - Alpha Tau Omega (Box 1)
  - Beta Phi Zeta (Box 1)
  - Beta Theta Pi (Box 1)
  - Chi Delta Phi (Box 2)
  - Chi Epsilon (Box 2)
  - Chi Phi (Box 2)
  - Chi Tau (Box 2)
  - Delta Delta Delta (Box 2)
  - Delta Gamma, 2014 (Box 12)
    Scope and Contents
    Three tri-fold table stands with information about the sorority, and one program from the 75th anniversary event in 2014.
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 2)
  - Delta Sigma Phi (Box 2)
  - Delta Sigma Theta (Box 2)
  - Delta Tau Delta (Box 2)
  - Kappa Alpha Order (Box 2)
  - Kappa Alpha Psi (Box 2)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma (Box 2)
  - Kappa Sigma (Box 2)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha (Box 2)
  - Latinas Promoviendo Comunidad, Lambda Pi Chi (Box 2)
  - La Unidad Latina, Lambda Upsilon Lambda (Box 2)
  - Mu Lambda (Box 2)
  - Omega Psi Phi (Box 2)
  - Phi Delta Theta (Box 2)
  - Phi Kappa Psi (Box 2)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma, 1959-1979 (Box 2)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma, 1992-1998 (Box 2)
  - Phi Mu (Box 3)
  - Pi Beta Phi (Box 3)
  - Pi Gamma Nu (Box 3)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha (Box 3)
  - Pi Kappa Phi (Box 3)
  - Psi Upsilon (Box 3)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Phy Kappa Sigma Newsletter (Box 3)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon (Box 3)
  - Sigma Chi, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
  - Sigma Chi, 1923-1965 (Box 4)
  - Sigma Gamma (Box 4)
  - Sigma Gamma Rho (Box 4)
  - Sigma Nu (Box 4)
  - Sigma Chi, 1923-1965 (Box 4)
  - Sigma Chi, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
  - Sigma Gamma (Box 4)
  - Sigma Gamma Rho (Box 4)
  - Sigma Nu (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon (Box 4)
  - Theta Beta Sigma (Box 4)
  - Theta Chi (Box 4)
  - Theta Nu Xi (Box 4)
  - Zeta Beta Tau, 1935-1956 (Box 4)
  - Zeta Beta Tau, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha (Box 4)
- Composite photographs, 1973-1993.
  Contains composite photographs of fraternity and sorority members (mostly fraternity groups).
  Ordered by date.
  - Composite photographs, 1973-1975 (Box 5)
  - Composite photographs, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Composite photographs, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Composite photographs, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Composite photographs, 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Composite photographs, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
  - Composite photographs, 1987-1993 (Box 10)
  - Psi Epsilon, 1973-1979 (Oversize-folder 1)